<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goal: Biodiversity on Ocean Health Index</title>
    <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/biodiversity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Goal: Biodiversity on Ocean Health Index</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/biodiversity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Habitat</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/biodiversity/habitats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/biodiversity/habitats/</guid>
      <description>PRESERVING COASTAL HABITATS This goal measures the status of coastal habitats that are particularly important in supporting large numbers of marine species.
CURRENT SCORE [Put a circle with Global Goal Score, like here: http://www.oceanhealthindex.org/methodology/goals/food-provision]
The current score indicates that the six habitats assessed- mangroves, coral reefs, seagrass beds, salt marshes, sea ice, and subtidal soft-bottom habitats- are still relatively healthy and intact on a global basis. However, the condition of the assessed habitats has declined over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Species</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/biodiversity/species/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/biodiversity/species/</guid>
      <description>This sub-goal assesses the health of all marine species present in a region, including endangered species and species in relatively good conditions. The presence of higher-risk species leads to a higher score.
 Data for this goal are also used in Sense of Places sub-goal: Iconic Species. It will be effective for goal keepers of Biodiversity and Sense of Place to work together on data gathering.
 Ideal Approach Ideally, you would find data for all species present in your region including information on their habitat ranges along with scientific studies that speak to the health of their populations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
