<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ocean Health Index</title>
    <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ocean Health Index</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Artisanal Fishing Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/artisanal-fishing-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/artisanal-fishing-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>ENSURING ACCESS TO ARTISANAL FISHING FOR LOCAL COMMUNITIES Artisanal fishing, often also called small-scale fishing, provides a critical source of food, nutrition, poverty alleviation and livelihood opportunities for many people around the world, in particular in developing nations.
Half the world’s fish harvest is captured by artisanal fishing families.
CURRENT SCORE [Put a circle with Global Goal Score, like here: http://www.oceanhealthindex.org/methodology/goals/food-provision]
The current score indicates that most regions are addressing and meeting the needs that people and communities have to fish artisanally by implementing government policies that permit or encourage them to do so and providing appropriate access to near-shore areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Natural Products</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/natural-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/natural-products/</guid>
      <description>Harvesting Food Products In many countries the harvest of non-food natural products is important for local economies and can also be traded internationally. The sustainable harvest of these products is therefore an important component of a healthy ocean. This goal assesses the ability of countries to maximize the sustainable harvest of living marine resources, such as corals, shells, seaweeds, and fish for the aquarium trade.
It does not include bioprospecting which focuses on potential (and largely unknowable and potentially infinite) value rather than current realized value, or non-living products such as oil and gas or mining products which by definition are not sustainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Carbon Storage</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/carbon-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/carbon-storage/</guid>
      <description>Highly productive coastal wetland ecosystems store substantially larger amount of carbon than terrestrial forests and have the highest sequestration rates of any habitats on earth. They are also threatened by under-regulated coastal development but are amenable to restoration and conservation efforts. This goal intends to capture the ability of the coastal habitats to remove carbon given their carbon uptake rate and health conditions. A score of 100 means all habitats that contribute to carbon removal are still intact or have been restored and they can function to their full carbon burial potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Coastal Protection</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/coastal-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/coastal-protection/</guid>
      <description>This goal aims to assess the amount of protection provided by marine and coastal habitats against flooding and erosion to coastal areas that people value, both inhabited (homes and other structures) and uninhabited (parks, special places, etc.). A score of 100 would indicate that these habitats are all still intact or have been restored to their reference conditions.
Habitat-based goals should be considered together during the data gathering process because the same data underly three goals: Carbon Storage, Coastal Protection, and Biodiversity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Tourism and Recreation</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/tourism-and-recreation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/tourism-and-recreation/</guid>
      <description>Tourism and recreation in coastal areas is a major component of thriving coastal communities and a measure of how much people value ocean systems, i.e. by traveling to coastal and ocean areas. This goal is not about the revenue or livelihoods that are generated by tourism and recreation (that is captured in the livelihoods goal, section 6F above) but instead captures the value that people have for experiencing and enjoying coastal areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Clean Waters</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/clean-waters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/clean-waters/</guid>
      <description>People value marine waters that are free of pollution and debris for aesthetic and health reasons. Contamination of waters comes from oil spills, chemicals, eutrophication, algal blooms, disease pathogens (e.g., fecal coliform, viruses, and parasites from sewage outflow), floating trash, and mass kills of organisms due to pollution. People are sensitive to these phenomena occurring in areas that they access for recreation or other purposes as well as for simply knowing that clean waters exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Global Ocean Health Index</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/news/2020-scores/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/news/2020-scores/</guid>
      <description>2020 Global Ocean Health Index by Gage Clawson &amp;amp; Melanie Frazier
Tue, Dec 01, 2020
2020 Global Ocean Health Index scores now available! We are proud to announce the 2020 Ocean Health Index scores (available here)!
This year marks the ninth global Ocean Health Index (OHI, for short) assessment measuring the sustainable delivery of 10 benefits, or goals, that people want and need from the ocean. The 2020 assessment was led by Gage Clawson, a former OHI Fellow, and Melanie Frazier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Baltic Health Index (BHI)</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/news/2020-baltic-health-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/news/2020-baltic-health-index/</guid>
      <description>2020 Baltic Health Index (BHI) by Melanie Frazier
Mon, Sep 21, 2020
A new open data tool for science and management The new assessment tool, the Baltic Health Index (BHI) evaluates comprehensively the health status of the Baltic Sea and has been calculated by researchers at the Stockholm Resilience Centre, Stockholm University, in cooperation with scientists in California who have established the well-known global Ocean Health Index (OHI) framework. The Ocean Health Index provides comprehensive, and quantitative assessments of progress towards healthy and sustainable oceans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Global Ocean Health Index Scores</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/news/2019-scores/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/news/2019-scores/</guid>
      <description>2019 Global Ocean Health Index Scores by Melanie Frazier
Tue, Dec 03, 2019
We are excited to announce the global Ocean Health Index (OHI) scores for 2019! The overall global Index score was 71, similar to scores in previous years.
This marks our eighth year of conducting the global assessment, and the second year hosting the Global Fellows Program to include University of California, Santa Barbara students with training to calculate the global scores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Transparency and Trust</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/news/transparency-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/news/transparency-trust/</guid>
      <description>On Building Transparency and Trust for Healthy New England Seas by Jenny Seifert
Mon, Nov 04, 2019
A case study about transparency in the Ocean Health Index In a world of increasingly complex decision making, transparency has become paramount. This is no exception in science and, specifically, in science-based management of natural resources.
Transparency is at the core of the Ocean Health Index (OHI). As a scientific evaluation of ocean health designed to inform management decisions that affect not just oceans but also people, it comes with the responsibility of transparency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Local Oceans</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/news/three-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/news/three-lessons/</guid>
      <description>Three Lessons for Using the Global Ocean Health Index to Assess Local Oceans by Jenny Seifert
Fri, Apr 26, 2019
Cross-posted at NCEAS
It just made sense. That was a theme I drew from conversations with four people involved in separate efforts to use the Ocean Health Index’s global framework to zoom in on ocean health in their particular regions to support local ocean planning.
The Index was designed to be useful to ocean planning around the world, and to be useful, it must be applicable to place-based management, which is how so many decisions that affect ocean health are made after all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canada</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/regions/canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/regions/canada/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conduct an OHI&#43;</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/ohi&#43;/conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/ohi&#43;/conduct/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/resources/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/resources/data/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Download</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/data-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/data-download/</guid>
      <description>We enthusiastically support the use of our data, but please cite our work.
Global OHI assessments require synthesizing data from nearly one hundred sources.
Data are prepared and scores calculated using freely available coding and version control software. In the interest of transparency and the promotion of scientific discovery, we freely provide the data and scripts used to calculate the global Ocean Health Index. However, we do not provide unaltered data obtained from other sources; to obtain these data you must go the original data sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/methodology/deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/methodology/deep-dive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OHI Assessments</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/ohi&#43;/ohi-assessments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/ohi&#43;/ohi-assessments/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/publications/</guid>
      <description>Peer-reviewed publications by the OHI team; * indicates open access.
OHI assessments Global website with all data and supplementary methods
Halpern et al. 2017, PLoS ONE*. Drivers and implications of change in global ocean health over the past 5 years. (website with interactive figures and maps)
Halpern et al. 2015, PLoS ONE*. Patterns and emerging trends in global ocean health. (2013 and updated 2012 global data)
Halpern et al. 2012, Nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scores over time</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/over-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/over-time/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub Goal: Wild Caught Fisheries</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/food-provision/wild-caught-fisheries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/food-provision/wild-caught-fisheries/</guid>
      <description>AN IMPORTANT GLOBAL FOOD SOURCE One of the most fundamental services the ocean provides is the provision of seafood. One in 7 people rely on fish as a daily source of protein, yet global catches have been declining steadily since peak catch in 1996 (Pauly and Zeller 2016). Given pressures on fisheries and projected increases in human population, it may become difficult to rely on wild-caught marine fish to meet basic nutritional needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Habitat</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/biodiversity/habitats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/biodiversity/habitats/</guid>
      <description>The Habitats sub-goal includes all habitats in the study area, and assess their health condition and coverage area.
 Habitat is included in the Biodiversity goal to provide a more complete picture of diversity in the system. This is because in global assessments assessed species data were limited and the diversity of habitats can be included with the assumption that healthier habitats mean healthier species. Therefore if you have comprehensive species assessments in your area you may not need to include all habitats as a sub-goal, instead only including living habitats (algae, corals) along with species in the Species sub-goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Iconic Species</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/sense-of-place/iconic-species/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/sense-of-place/iconic-species/</guid>
      <description>Iconic species are those that are relevant to local cultural identity through a species’ relationship to one or more of the following: 1) traditional activities such as fishing, hunting or commerce; 2) local ethnic or religious practices; 3) existence value; and 4) locally-recognized aesthetic value (e.g., touristic attractions/common subjects for art such as whales). Habitat-forming species are not included in this definition of iconic species, nor are species that are harvested solely for economic or utilitarian purposes (even though they may be iconic to a sector or individual).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Lasting Special Places</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/sense-of-place/lasting-special-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/sense-of-place/lasting-special-places/</guid>
      <description>This sub-goal focuses on those geographic locations that hold particular value for aesthetic, spiritual, cultural, recreational or existence reasons, and assesses how well they are protected.
 This sub-goal makes use of protected areas, and some of the same information gathered on projected areas can be used to create resilience data layers like Marine Protected Areas.
 Ideal Approach Ideally, you would be able to survey everyone in your region and produce a list of all the places they consider special, and then assess how well they are protected relative to a desired state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Livelihoods</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/livelihoods-and-economies/livelihoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/livelihoods-and-economies/livelihoods/</guid>
      <description>This sub-goal describes livelihood quantity and quality for people living on the coast. Livelihoods includes two equally important sub-components, the number of jobs, which is a proxy for livelihood quantity, and the per capita average annual wages, which is a proxy for job quality.
Ideal Approach Ideally, this sub-goal would speak to the quality and quantity of marine jobs in an area. It would encompass all the marine sectors that supply jobs and wages to coastal communities, incorporating information on the sustainability of different sectors while also telling about the working conditions and job satisfaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Mariculture</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/food-provision/mariculture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/food-provision/mariculture/</guid>
      <description>AN INCREASINGLY IMPORTANT SOURCE OF FOOD As humanity’s population continues to expand, we must increasingly rely upon new and improved methods for cultivating food on land and in the ocean. The term aquaculture refers to the cultivation in water (fresh and saltwater) of animals or plants for human consumption. Mariculture refers to the commercial harvest of seafood that is farm-raised in the ocean and along the coast.
Aquaculture is the fastest growing animal food production sector in the world!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Species</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/biodiversity/species/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/biodiversity/species/</guid>
      <description>This sub-goal assesses the health of all marine species present in a region, including endangered species and species in relatively good conditions. The presence of higher-risk species leads to a higher score.
 Data for this goal are also used in Sense of Places sub-goal: Iconic Species. It will be effective for goal keepers of Biodiversity and Sense of Place to work together on data gathering.
 Ideal Approach Ideally, you would find data for all species present in your region including information on their habitat ranges along with scientific studies that speak to the health of their populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal:Economies</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/livelihoods-and-economies/economies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/goals/livelihoods-and-economies/economies/</guid>
      <description>Economies captures the economic value associated with marine industries using revenue from marine sectors. It is composed of a single component, revenue.
Ideal Approach Ideally, revenue data would be collected for all coastal regions, and traced from sectors both directly and indirectly related to marine industries. When these data are not available it is possible to use revenue data at a larger scale and adapt them to a coastal area based on the population distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporters</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/supporters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/supporters/</guid>
      <description>We are grateful for the generous support from the Pacific Life Foundation and the Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation, as well as our founding contributors for helping us build the Ocean Health Index from the beginning. Without their generosity of intellectual and financial support the Ocean Health Index would not be a reality.
The Pacific Life Foundation The Pacific Life Foundation made a commitment in 2011 to become the Founding Presenting Sponsor of the Ocean Health Index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/team/</guid>
      <description>This team develops scientific methods, communicates results to governments, marine managers, scientists and the public, manages current operations and directs future development of the Ocean Health Index project. Ben Halpern has been with the project since planning began in 2008. The team gratefully acknowledges the individuals, foundations, organizations and corporations listed as Contributors and Sustaining Partners. This project would not exist without them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/resources/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/resources/tools/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
