<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goal: Sense of Place on Ocean Health Index</title>
    <link>https://ohi-science.github.io/ohi-website/methodology/goals/sense-of-place/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Goal: Sense of Place on Ocean Health Index</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ohi-science.github.io/ohi-website/methodology/goals/sense-of-place/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Iconic Species</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.github.io/ohi-website/methodology/goals/sense-of-place/iconic-species/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.github.io/ohi-website/methodology/goals/sense-of-place/iconic-species/</guid>
      <description>Iconic species are those that are relevant to local cultural identity through a species’ relationship to one or more of the following: 1) traditional activities such as fishing, hunting or commerce; 2) local ethnic or religious practices; 3) existence value; and 4) locally-recognized aesthetic value (e.g., touristic attractions/common subjects for art such as whales). Habitat-forming species are not included in this definition of iconic species, nor are species that are harvested solely for economic or utilitarian purposes (even though they may be iconic to a sector or individual).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Lasting Special Places</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.github.io/ohi-website/methodology/goals/sense-of-place/lasting-special-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.github.io/ohi-website/methodology/goals/sense-of-place/lasting-special-places/</guid>
      <description>This sub-goal focuses on those geographic locations that hold particular value for aesthetic, spiritual, cultural, recreational or existence reasons, and assesses how well they are protected.
 This sub-goal makes use of protected areas, and some of the same information gathered on projected areas can be used to create resilience data layers like Marine Protected Areas.
 Ideal Approach Ideally, you would be able to survey everyone in your region and produce a list of all the places they consider special, and then assess how well they are protected relative to a desired state.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
