<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guidance on Ocean Health Index</title>
    <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guidance on Ocean Health Index</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Artisanal Fishing Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/artisanal-fishing-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/artisanal-fishing-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>Artisanal fishing, often also called small-scale fishing, provides a critical source of food, nutrition, poverty alleviation, and livelihoods for many people around the world. This resource is particularly important in developing nations. As opposed to large, commercial fisheries that usually involve industrial, energy-intensive vessels and long trips, artisanal fisheries refer to households, cooperatives or small firms that use relatively small amounts of capital, energy and small fishing vessels (if any), make relatively short fishing trips, and use fish mainly for local consumption or trade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Natural Products</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/natural-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/natural-products/</guid>
      <description>This goal assesses the ability of countries to maximize the sustainable harvest of living marine resources that are not consumed as food by humans, such as sponges, fishoil and fishmeal, shells, seaweeds, mangrove wood, and fish for the aquarium trade.
Similar to Food Provisions, this goal is trying to capture the value of goods sustainably harvested by the ocean. While Food Provision focuses on goods for human consumption, Natural Products assesses non-food goods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Carbon Storage</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/carbon-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/carbon-storage/</guid>
      <description>This goal captures the ability of coastal marine environments to store carbon in key habitats.
Highly productive coastal wetland ecosystems store substantially more carbon than terrestrial forests and have the highest sequestration rates of any habitats on earth. They are also threatened by under-regulated coastal development but are amenable to restoration and conservation efforts. This goal intends to capture the ability of the coastal habitats to remove carbon given the amount of carbon they store and/or their carbon uptake rate and the condition of the habitat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Coastal Protection</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/coastal-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/coastal-protection/</guid>
      <description>This goal assesses the amount of protection provided by marine and coastal habitats against flooding and erosion to coastal areas that people value, both inhabited (homes and other structures) and uninhabited (parks, special places, etc.).
A score of 100 indicates habitats that provide coastal protection are intact or have been restored to their reference conditions.
Habitat-based goals (Storage, Coastal Protection, and Biodiversity) should be considered together during the data gathering process because the same data underly these goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Tourism and Recreation</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/tourism-and-recreation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/tourism-and-recreation/</guid>
      <description>Tourism and recreation in coastal areas is a major component of thriving coastal communities and a measure of how much people value ocean systems. A score of 100 means a region sustainably realizes its full recreational potential.
This goal is not about the revenue or livelihoods that are generated by tourism and recreation (that is captured in other goals) but instead captures the value that people have for experiencing and enjoying coastal areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Clean Waters</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/clean-waters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/clean-waters/</guid>
      <description>People value marine waters that are free of pollution and debris for aesthetic and health reasons. Contamination of waters can come from land and ocean-based sources and cause many problems. Pollution can result in contaminated marine food, damage to mariculture, toxic blooms, beach closures, and mass kills of organisms. People are sensitive to these phenomena occurring in areas they access for recreation or other purposes but people even appreciate clean waters they do not directly use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Economies</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/economies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/economies/</guid>
      <description>Economies is a component of the Livelihoods and Economies goal. The Economies subgoal captures the economic value of marine-related industries. A score of 100 indicates that a coastal region has maximized their revenue from the marine sector.
Before embarking on the Economies subgoal, consider how you want to structure the larger goal. The global assessment is composed of two equally important sub-goals, livelihoods and economies, which are assessed across as many marine-related sectors as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Habitat</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/habitats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/habitats/</guid>
      <description>The Habitat sub-goal is a component of the Biodiversity goal and assesses the condition of habitats that support many species.
Habitat-based goals (Storage, Coastal Protection, and Biodiversity) should be considered together during the data gathering process because the same data underly these goals.
Practical Guidance STEP 1: Do you need a habitat subgoal?
Habitat is included in the Biodiversity goal to provide a more complete picture of the condition of the species in the study area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Iconic Species</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/iconic-species/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/iconic-species/</guid>
      <description>Iconic species is a component of the Sense of Place goal which aims to capture how well we are protecting the local coastal and marine systems that we value as part of our cultural identity. For the iconic species subgoal, a score of 100 means that all the culturally important marine species in a region are doing well.
Practical Guidance This sub-goal assesses the condition of local marine species that are iconic to a region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Lasting Special Places</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/lasting-special-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/lasting-special-places/</guid>
      <description>Lasting Special Places is a component of the Sense of Place goal which aims to capture how well we are protecting the local coastal and marine systems that we value as part of our cultural identity.
For the Lasting Special Places subgoal, a score of 100 indicates marine regions that hold particular value for aesthetic, spiritual, cultural, recreational or existence reasons are well-protected and healthy.
Marine protected areas can also be used to measure resilience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Livelihoods</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/livelihoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/livelihoods/</guid>
      <description>Livelihoods is a component of the Livelihoods and Economies goal. This subgoal describes the quantity and quality of marine related employment available to people. Livelihoods includes two equally important sub-components, the number of jobs, which is a proxy for livelihood quantity, and the per capita average annual wages, which is a proxy for job quality.
A score of 100 indicates that a coastal region has maximized the quantity and quality of jobs in the marine sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Mariculture</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/mariculture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/mariculture/</guid>
      <description>Mariculture is a component of the Food Provision goal. This subgoal measures the ability to maximize the amount of seafood from farm-raised facilities without compromising sustainability.
A score of 100 means that a region is growing the greatest amount of farmed seafood possible based on its potential (where its maximum potential is estimated in different ways depending on the assessment) and without compromising future production. Sustainable production is acheived by not compromising water quality, avoiding unsustainable sources of feed and sources for replenishing cultivated species, and ensuring the safety and quality of the product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Species</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/species/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/species/</guid>
      <description>The Species sub-goal is a component of the Biodiversity goal and assesses the condition of all marine species present in a region, including both endangered species and those in relatively good condition.
Data for this goal is also used in Sense of Place sub-goal: Iconic Species. It will be effective for goal keepers of Biodiversity and Sense of Place to work together on data gathering.
Practical Guidance Ideally, every marine species in an assessment area will have spatial data describing their location and descriptions of their popoulation health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub Goal: Wild Caught Fisheries</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/wild-caught-fisheries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/guidance/wild-caught-fisheries/</guid>
      <description>Fisheries is part of the Food Provision goal. This subgoal measures the amount of seafood sustainably harvested in a given EEZ or region through any means for human consumption, and thus includes wild-caught commercial fisheries, mariculture, artisanal-scale and recreational fisheries. The Food Provision goals aim to maximize the amount of sustainably produced seafood from wild or ocean-cultured stocks so both over- or under- harvesting should be penalized. A score of 100 means the country or region is harvesting seafood to the ecosystem’s production potential in an sustainable manner.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
