<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goal: Livelihoods and Economies on Ocean Health Index</title>
    <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/livelihoods-and-economies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Goal: Livelihoods and Economies on Ocean Health Index</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/livelihoods-and-economies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Livelihoods</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/livelihoods-and-economies/livelihoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/livelihoods-and-economies/livelihoods/</guid>
      <description>MARINE ENVIRONMENTS PROVIDE JOB OPPORTUNITIES This sub-goal describes the quantity and quality of marine-related jobs for people living on the coast, such as: commercial fishing, mariculture, tourism and recreation, and whale watching.
CURRENT SCORE [Put a circle with Global Goal Score, like here: http://www.oceanhealthindex.org/methodology/goals/food-provision]
The current score indicates that jobs and wages have declined substantially compared to their reference points leaving much room for improvement.
Livelihood scores have decreased by ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal:Economies</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/livelihoods-and-economies/economies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/livelihoods-and-economies/economies/</guid>
      <description>MARINE ENVIRONMENTS SUPPORT ECONOMIES The Economies goal captures the economic value associated with marine industries using revenue from marine sectors, such as commercial fishing, mariculture, tourism and recreation, shipping and transportation, whale watching, ports and harbors, ship and boat building, and renewable energy production.
CURRENT SCORE [Put a circle with Global Goal Score, like here: http://www.oceanhealthindex.org/methodology/goals/food-provision]
The current global score indicates most coastal economies are keeping pace with growth in GDP and have sustained no recent losses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
