<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goal: Biodiversity on Ocean Health Index</title>
    <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Goal: Biodiversity on Ocean Health Index</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://oceanhealthindex.org/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Habitat</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/habitats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/habitats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;preserving-marine-habitats&#34;&gt;PRESERVING MARINE HABITATS&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This goal measures the status of marine habitats that support large numbers of marine species.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-score&#34;&gt;CURRENT SCORE&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;score-gauge&#34; data-region-id=&#34;0&#34; data-goal-code=&#34;HAB&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The current score indicates that the eight assessed habitats - kelp forests, mangroves, coral reefs, seagrass beds, salt marshes, sea ice, subtidal soft-bottom habitats, and tidal flats- have experienced declines (relative to recent historical periods) but are still relatively intact on a global basis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This sub-goal score is higher than what is reported by numerous scientific studies and media reports. There is no question that the extent of mangrove forests, salt marshes and seagrass beds have declined considerably compared to historic levels; that sea ice is steadily declining (especially in the Arctic) and that a number of pressures now seriously challenge coral reefs. Many people have commented that the OHI does not accurately reflect the magnitude of this habitat loss.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Species</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/species/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/species/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;preserving-marine-species&#34;&gt;PRESERVING MARINE SPECIES&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This goal measures the conservation status of marine species.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-score&#34;&gt;CURRENT SCORE&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;score-gauge&#34; data-region-id=&#34;0&#34; data-goal-code=&#34;SPP&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A high score indicates that most native marine species in a country are not identified as threatened or vulnerable by the IUCN which monitors the status of many species.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The current score indicates a potential risk of losing a significant proportion of marine species diversity across the globe. The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species estimates that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iucnredlist.org/search/stats&#34;&gt;35% of all assessed species&lt;/a&gt; are threatened with extinction, including 37% of species of sharks and rays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
