<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goal: Biodiversity on Ocean Health Index</title>
    <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Goal: Biodiversity on Ocean Health Index</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://oceanhealthindex.org/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Habitat</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/habitats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/habitats/</guid>
      <description>PRESERVING MARINE HABITATS This goal measures the status of marine habitats that support large numbers of marine species.&#xA;CURRENT SCORE The current score indicates that the eight assessed habitats - kelp forests, mangroves, coral reefs, seagrass beds, salt marshes, sea ice, subtidal soft-bottom habitats, and tidal flats- have experienced declines (relative to recent historical periods) but are still relatively intact on a global basis.&#xA;This sub-goal score is higher than what is reported by numerous scientific studies and media reports.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Species</title>
      <link>https://oceanhealthindex.org/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/species/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oceanhealthindex.org/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/species/</guid>
      <description>PRESERVING MARINE SPECIES This goal measures the conservation status of marine species.&#xA;CURRENT SCORE A high score indicates that most native marine species in a country are not identified as threatened or vulnerable by the IUCN which monitors the status of many species.&#xA;The current score indicates a potential risk of losing a significant proportion of marine species diversity across the globe. The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species estimates that 35% of all assessed species are threatened with extinction, including 37% of species of sharks and rays.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
