<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ocean Health Index</title>
    <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ocean Health Index</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Artisanal Fishing Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/artisanal-fishing-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/artisanal-fishing-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>Artisanal fishing, often also called small-scale fishing, provides a critical source of food, nutrition, poverty alleviation, and livelihoods for many people around the world. This resource is particularly important in developing nations. As opposed to large, commercial fisheries that usually involve industrial, energy-intensive vessels and long trips, artisanal fisheries refer to households, cooperatives or small firms that use relatively small amounts of capital, energy and small fishing vessels (if any), make relatively short fishing trips, and use fish mainly for local consumption or trade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Natural Products</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/natural-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/natural-products/</guid>
      <description>This goal assesses the ability of countries to maximize the sustainable harvest of living marine resources that are not consumed as food by humans, such as sponges, fishoil and fishmeal, shells, seaweeds, mangrove wood, and fish for the aquarium trade.
 Similar to Food Provisions, this goal is trying to capture the value of goods sustainably harvested by the ocean. While Food Provision focuses on goods for human consumption, Natural Products assesses non-food goods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Coastal Protection</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/coastal-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/coastal-protection/</guid>
      <description>This goal assesses the amount of protection provided by marine and coastal habitats against flooding and erosion to coastal areas that people value, both inhabited (homes and other structures) and uninhabited (parks, special places, etc.).
A score of 100 indicates habitats that provide coastal protection are intact or have been restored to their reference conditions.
 Habitat-based goals (Storage, Coastal Protection, and Biodiversity) should be considered together during the data gathering process because the same data underly these goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Tourism and Recreation</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/tourism-and-recreation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/tourism-and-recreation/</guid>
      <description>Tourism and recreation in coastal areas is a major component of thriving coastal communities and a measure of how much people value ocean systems, i.e. by traveling to coastal and ocean areas. This goal is not about the revenue or livelihoods that are generated by tourism and recreation (that is captured in the livelihoods goal, section 6F above) but instead captures the value that people have for experiencing and enjoying coastal areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidance: Clean Waters</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/clean-waters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/clean-waters/</guid>
      <description>People value marine waters that are free of pollution and debris for aesthetic and health reasons. Contamination of waters comes from oil spills, chemicals, disease pathogens (e.g., fecal coliform, viruses, and parasites from sewage outflow), and trash. Pollution can result in contaminated marine food resources, damage to mariculture, toxic blooms, beach closures, and mass kills of organisms. People are sensitive to these phenomena occurring in areas that they access for recreation or other purposes as well as for simply knowing that clean waters exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biodiversity: Habitat</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/habitats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/habitats/</guid>
      <description>The Habitat sub-goal is part of the Biodiversity goal and assesses the condition of habitats that support many species.
 Habitat-based goals (Storage, Coastal Protection, and Biodiversity) should be considered together during the data gathering process because the same data underly these goals.
 Practical Guidance STEP 1: Do you need a habitat subgoal?
Habitat is included in the Biodiversity goal to provide a more complete picture of the condition of the species in the study area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biodiversity: Species</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/species/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/species/</guid>
      <description>The Species sub-goal is part of the Biodiversity goal and assesses the condition of all marine species present in a region, including endangered species and species in relatively good condition.
 Data for this goal may also used in Sense of Place sub-goal: Iconic Species. It will be effective for goal keepers of Biodiversity and Sense of Place to work together on data gathering.
 Practical Guidance Ideally, every marine species living in the assessment area will have spatial data describing their location and descriptions of their popoulation health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub Goal: Wild Caught Fisheries</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/wild-caught-fisheries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/wild-caught-fisheries/</guid>
      <description>This goal measures the amount of seafood sustainably harvested in a given EEZ or region through any means for use primarily in human consumption and thus includes wild-caught commercial fisheries, mariculture, artisanal-scale and recreational fisheries. The Food Provision goals aim to maximize the amount of sustainably produced seafood from wild or ocean-cultured stocks so both over- or under- harvesting should be penalized. A score of 100 means the country or region is harvesting seafood to the ecosystem’s production potential in an sustainable manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Iconic Species</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/iconic-species/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/iconic-species/</guid>
      <description>Iconic species are those that are relevant to local cultural identity through a species’ relationship to one or more of the following: 1) traditional activities such as fishing, hunting or commerce; 2) local ethnic or religious practices; 3) existence value; and 4) locally-recognized aesthetic value (e.g., touristic attractions/common subjects for art such as whales). Habitat-forming species are not included in this definition of iconic species, nor are species that are harvested solely for economic or utilitarian purposes (even though they may be iconic to a sector or individual).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Lasting Special Places</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/lasting-special-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/lasting-special-places/</guid>
      <description>This sub-goal focuses on those geographic locations that hold particular value for aesthetic, spiritual, cultural, recreational or existence reasons, and assesses how well they are protected.
 This sub-goal makes use of protected areas, and some of the same information gathered on projected areas can be used to create resilience data layers like Marine Protected Areas.
 Ideal Approach Ideally, you would be able to survey everyone in your region and produce a list of all the places they consider special, and then assess how well they are protected relative to a desired state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Livelihoods</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/livelihoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/livelihoods/</guid>
      <description>This sub-goal describes livelihood quantity and quality for people living on the coast. Livelihoods includes two equally important sub-components, the number of jobs, which is a proxy for livelihood quantity, and the per capita average annual wages, which is a proxy for job quality.
A score of 100 indicates that a coastal region has maximized the quantity and quality of jobs in the marine sector.
Before embarking on the Livelihoods subgoal, consider how you want to structure the larger goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Mariculture</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/mariculture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/mariculture/</guid>
      <description>The Mariculture subgoal measures the ability to maximize the amount of seafood from farm-raised facilities without compromising the ocean’s ability to sustainably provide food now and in the future.
A score of 100 means that a region is growing the greatest amount of farmed seafood possible based on its potential (where its maximum potential is estimated in different ways depending on the assessment) and without compromising future production. Sustainable production is acheived by not compromising water quality, avoiding unsustainable sources of feed and sources for replenishing cultivated species, and ensuring the safety and quality of the product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal:Economies</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/economies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/guidance/economies/</guid>
      <description>Economies captures the economic value of marine-related industries. A score of 100 indicates that a coastal region has maximized their revenue from the marine sector.
Before embarking on the Economies subgoal, consider how you want to structure the larger goal. The global assessment is composed of two equally important sub-goals, livelihoods and economies, which are assessed across as many marine-related sectors as possible. Livelihoods includes two equally important sub-components, the number of jobs, which is a proxy for livelihood quantity, and the per capita average annual wages, which is a proxy for job quality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
