<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goals on Ocean Health Index</title>
    <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Goals on Ocean Health Index</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Artisanal Fishing Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/artisanal-fishing-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/artisanal-fishing-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>ENSURING ACCESS TO ARTISANAL FISHING FOR LOCAL COMMUNITIES This goal measures whether people who need to fish on a small, local scale have the opportunity to do so.
CURRENT SCORE [Put a circle with Global Goal Score, like here: http://www.oceanhealthindex.org/methodology/goals/food-provision]
The current score indicates that most regions are addressing and meeting the needs that people and communities have to fish artisanally by implementing government policies that permit or encourage them to do so and providing appropriate access to near-shore areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Carbon Storage</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/carbon-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/carbon-storage/</guid>
      <description>PRESERVING HABITATS THAT ABSORB CARBON This goal captures the ability of coastal habitats to store carbon given the amount of carbon they store and their health.
CURRENT SCORE [Put a circle with Global Goal Score, like here: http://www.oceanhealthindex.org/methodology/goals/food-provision]
The current score indicates that although, in many places, these habitats remain healthy and intact, a significant number have declined significantly since 1980 and more declines are likely in the near future. More protection and restoration must occur if they are to sequester and store the maximum amount of carbon possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Clean Waters</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/clean-waters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/clean-waters/</guid>
      <description>CLEAN WATERS ARE IMPORTANT The Clean Water goal captures the degree to which local waters are unpolluted by human-made causes.
CURRENT SCORE [Put a circle with Global Goal Score, like here: http://www.oceanhealthindex.org/methodology/goals/food-provision]
The current score indicates that there large opportunities for improvement. This goal scores highest when the contamination level is zero.Reducing the inflow of chemicals, nutrients, human and animal wastes and trash requires remedial actions at every level of society as well as adjustments to behavior on an individual basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Coastal Protection</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/coastal-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/coastal-protection/</guid>
      <description>PRESERVING HABITATS THAT SAFEGUARD SHORES This goal aims to assess the amount of protection provided by marine and coastal habitats against flooding and erosion to coastal areas that people value, both inhabited (homes and other structures) and uninhabited (parks, special places, etc.).
CURRENT SCORE [Put a circle with Global Goal Score, like here: http://www.oceanhealthindex.org/methodology/goals/food-provision]
The current score indicates that although, in many places, these habitats remain healthy and intact, the extents of all five habitats have been substantially reduced or degraded when compared to their reference years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Natural Products</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/natural-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/natural-products/</guid>
      <description>HARVESTING OCEAN RESOURCES SUSTAINABLY This goal assesses how well countries are maximizing the sustainable harvest of non-food marine resources.
CURRENT SCORE [Put a circle with Global Goal Score, like here: http://www.oceanhealthindex.org/methodology/goals/food-provision]
The current score indicates that many regions have potential to improve sustainable harvests of natural products, either by eliminating overharvesting, increasing harvests that are too low, or reducing the pressures that decrease potential harvests.
Natural products scores have decreased by ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Tourism and Recreation</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/tourism-and-recreation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/tourism-and-recreation/</guid>
      <description>THE DRAW OF THE OCEAN Coastal and marine tourism is a vital part of a country’s economy. This goal measures participation in sustainable tourism to coastal regions.
CURRENT SCORE [Put a circle with Global Goal Score, like here: http://www.oceanhealthindex.org/methodology/goals/food-provision]
Low scores for many regions are due to unsafe or unappealing conditions owing to poverty, political turmoil, war or other volatile conditions and scores will likely be depressed until those fundamental conditions improve.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
