<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>What is OHI on Ocean Health Index</title>
    <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in What is OHI on Ocean Health Index</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporters</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/supporters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/supporters/</guid>
      <description>Our founding contributors go above and beyond in their generosity of intellectual and financial support. Without these forward-thinking leaders, the Ocean Health Index would not be a reality.
FOUNDING PRESENTING SPONSOR The Pacific Life Foundation has a strong tradition of creating positive societal change through its grant making program. The Foundation made a commitment in 2011 to become the Founding Presenting Sponsor of the Ocean Health Index as it has the potential to stimulate a reversal in ocean health, from negative to positive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/about/team/</guid>
      <description>This team develops scientific methods, communicates results to governments, marine managers, scientists and the public, manages current operations and directs future development of the Ocean Health Index project. Ben Halpern has been with the project since planning began in 2008. The team gratefully acknowledges the individuals, foundations, organizations and corporations listed as Contributors and Sustaining Partners. This project would not exist without them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
