<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goal: Biodiversity on Ocean Health Index</title>
    <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Goal: Biodiversity on Ocean Health Index</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Habitat</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/habitats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/habitats/</guid>
      <description>PRESERVING MARINE HABITATS This goal measures the status of marine habitats that are particularly important in supporting large numbers of marine species.
CURRENT SCORE  The current score indicates that the six habitats assessed- mangroves, coral reefs, seagrass beds, salt marshes, sea ice, and subtidal soft-bottom habitats- are still relatively healthy and intact on a global basis.
Generally we know that there is a global decline in habitat extent and health, but for the most part this is hard to monitor, and many of the data associated with these habitats are of poor quality (aside from mangroves and sea ice).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sub-Goal: Species</title>
      <link>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/species/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohi-science.org/OHI-website/global-scores/goal-scores/biodiversity/species/</guid>
      <description>PRESERVING MARINE SPECIES This goal measures the conservation status of marine species.
CURRENT SCORE  A high score indicates that most native species in a given country are free from risk (invasive species are excluded), and it is 0 when up to 75% of native species are at high risk (this is a level comparable to prehistoric mass extinctions).
It is important to recognize that this score represents a small sample of existing marine biodiversity, since IUCN data currently only exists for a small percentage of known marine species.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
