<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>What is OHI on Ocean Health Index</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in What is OHI on Ocean Health Index</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact OHI For all inquiries about the OHI, contact&#xA;Ben Halpern at halpern@nceas.ucsb.edu</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OHI Fellows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/ohifellows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/ohifellows/</guid>
      <description>2024 Fellows Anna Ramji Anna Ramji grew up hiking and fishing along the Eastern Sierra Nevada mountain range, where she developed an interest in ecology and the impacts of climate change on native ecosystems. She spent much of her childhood on Northern Californian beaches, developing a profound respect for the power, beauty, and importance of the Pacific Ocean. During her time as an undergraduate at the University of California, Berkeley, she worked as a research assistant and laboratory manager at Caldwell Laboratory, studying stomatopods and several species of octopus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/people/</guid>
      <description>The Ocean Health Index team develops scientific methods and calculates scores, manages current operations and directs future development, and communicates results to governments, marine managers, scientists, and the public.&#xA;Ben Halpern has been with the project since planning began in 2008.&#xA;The team gratefully acknowledges the individuals, foundations, organizations and corporations listed as Contributors and Sustaining Partners. This project would not exist without them.&#xA;Ben Halpern&#xA;Lead Scientist&#xA;Melanie Frazier</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/publications/</guid>
      <description>Peer-reviewed publications by the OHI team; * indicates open access.&#xA;OHI assessments Global all data and supplementary methods&#xA;Halpern et al. 2017, PLoS ONE*. Drivers and implications of change in global ocean health over the past 5 years.&#xA;Halpern et al. 2015, PLoS ONE*. Patterns and emerging trends in global ocean health. (2013 and updated 2012 global data)&#xA;Halpern et al. 2012, Nature. An index to assess the health and benefits of the global ocean.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/supporters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/supporters/</guid>
      <description>We are grateful for the generous support from the Pacific Life Foundation and the Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation, as well as our founding contributors for helping us build the Ocean Health Index from the beginning. Without their generosity of intellectual and financial support the Ocean Health Index would not be a reality.&#xA;The Pacific Life Foundation The Pacific Life Foundation made a commitment in 2011 to become the Founding Presenting Sponsor of the Ocean Health Index.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
